之前从未有人从这越过狱
No one's ever broken out of this place before,
更别说只有一周时间来策划
let alone with a week to plan, so you tell these people
你去告诉那帮人 我会尽力助他越狱
I'm gonna break this guy out of here
甚至不惜付出生命的代价
or I'm going to die trying.
我需要你留下做我耳目
You're going to stay on as my ears.
向我汇报所有你听说的消息
You'll report back to me everything you hear
当我不在场的时候
when I'm not around.
我知道你有个哥哥在外面接应你
I know you've got a brother helping on the outside,
他跑去找了我女友
I know he ran into my girlfriend,
还知道他从她那儿抢走了我的书
and I know he took a book from her that belongs to me.
他们抢走了的我的宝贝
This is what they took from me.
所以说白了
So let's be clear,
这才是我关心的事情
this is what matters to me.
而不是你
Not you.
更不是你的书
And not your book.
LJ怎样? 莎拉怎样?
How's LJ? How's Sara?
他们说都很好
They told me they're fine.
你还有什么瞒着我?
What are you not telling me?
并非只有你一个牵涉其中
You're not the only one affected
他们杀了莎拉头割下弃在盒中
They killed Sara and put her head in a box
他们还抓走了我的儿子
And they got my son
你没有时间了
you are running out of the time
什么东西
what's that?
一只老鼠
A rat.
YYeTs人人影视字幕组出品
最新最快字幕下载请登录：www.YYeTs.net
■
字幕：YYeTs人人影视字幕组  后期：梁良
J.P盖迪(美首位亿万富翁)有一个成功的口诀
J.P. Getty had a formula for success.
早早起身 好好工作
"Rise early, work hard,
钱包鼓鼓
strike oil."
阿历克斯我只是来喝杯水
Just trying to get a drink of water, Alex.
作为你精湛技艺的虔诚的崇拜者
As a devoted student of your work and skills,
我真的非常期待
I-I really look forward
和你一起共同实施计划 迈克
to progress on your plan, Michael.
我期待你能别老缠着我
I'm looking forward to you getting off my back.
臭小子 欢迎你来索纳监狱
Buenos, welcome to Sona.
那是你的皮夹子吗?
Is that your wallet?
该死的皮夹子
Dame tu billetera.
抱歉 我不懂西班牙语
No hablo Espal, uh?
你明白我说的意思
You know what I said.
不明白
No.
你不该这么回答的
That's the wrong answer.
只要你搞定了 我随时可以跟你出去
I am so ready to get out of here anytime you are.
斯科菲尔德有访客
Scofield,visita.
scofield, you have a visitor.
长夜漫漫啊
You look like you had a long night.
没错
Yeah.
我花了很久喂老鼠吃巧克力
I spent most of it feeding chocolate to a rat.
这几天都没有整块时间可以开工的
I don't have a whole lot to work with these days.
她拿走了那本书 鸟类导读
She's got the book, man, the bird guide.
她发现了
She worked it out.
那我们手上没有筹码了
So we have no leverage.
-没了 -告诉我
-No. -Tell me
当你递上那本书的时候
When you were handing over the book,
你有没有要LJ和莎拉的最新照片
did you ask for a recent photo of LJ and Sara?
是的
Yeah.
那照片呢?
And where is it?
她给我看了照片 但是不肯给我
She showed me the pictures, but she wouldn't let me keep them.
老弟 我可没有资格和他们谈条件
Man, I'm not in a position to bargain with these people.
我是说他们已经被激怒了
I mean, they're pissed.
明天就得越狱出来
You break out tomorrow.
让我们只关注越狱一事吧
Let's just focus on that.
回到正题上来
Let's keep on track.
好吧
All right.
当我在狱内开工的时候
While I'm working from the inside,
我需要你去准备下
I need you to take care of what happens
逃出来后的事宜
once we're outside.
需要辆车逃之夭夭
We're going to need a getaway vehicle,
不惹眼的那种
something inconspicuous.
不管你找到什么车 明天下午3点
Whatever you find, it has to be parked
必须停在离这半英里的地方
a half mile from here by 3:00 p.m. tomorrow.
你是说凌晨3点?
You mean a.m.
不 确实是下午
No, I mean p.m.
林肯 我们没得选
We don't have a choice, Linc.
昨晚上我做了些测试
I ran some tests last night.
军方吉普车夜晚在周边巡逻
Military jeeps patrol the perimeter at night.
晚上根本无法分辨他们在什么方位
There's no way of telling where they're going to be in the dark.
整晚上他们都在外面巡逻
They were out there all night.
我们需要夜幕遮掩 不能就
We need the dark, we can't just Just
拜托别争了
Please.
因为明天就要动手了
Because we're doing this tomorrow.
中午时分行动
In the middle of the day.
你看谁呢?
Who're you looking at?
那家伙
That guy.
我认识他
I know him.
小麦迪朋友 我需要块手表
McGrady, my friend, I'm going to need a watch.
或许要2块
Maybe two.
我不会问其中原因了
I'm not even going to ask why.
我还需要些双筒望远镜
I'm also going to need some binoculars.
老威廉倒是有个
Old Guillermo has a pair.
他根本不可能卖给你
There's no way he'll sell them to you, man.
但是望远镜也不算难搞定
But they shouldn't be hard to get.
我上哪里能找到他?
Where can I find this guy?
我们明天行动
We leave tomorrow.
这个
This
这是我们逃离索纳监狱的方案
This is how we're getting out of Sona.
逃出监狱隔栏
Getting out of the cell block
应该不是什么问题
shouldn't be a problem.
围壁栅栏很容易突破
The grate and bars are weak,
但是我们需要些绳索
but we're going to need some kind of rope,
还有梯子 这样可以从另外边下去
some kind of ladder, to let us down on the other side.
那就是我标出最安全的线路
That's why I figured out the safest
从这里到栅栏的那个洞的原因
line from here to the hole in the fence.
我们白天动手
We do it in the day,
只有塔楼上的2个警卫能看到我们
we'll only be visible to the two guard towers.
周边警卫的情况很难说
The perimeter guards are less predictable,
但是他们只有在晚上才出没
but they're only on at night.
大白天的穿越监狱逃跑?
Scurrying across the field in the middle of the day?
这是唯一避开巡逻吉普车的方法
It's the only way to avoid the jeep patrol.
明天下午2点 监狱大院里会有场球赛
Now, in the yard tomorrow, there's a soccer game at 2:00.
应该会吸引狱内很多注意力
That should prove some distraction inside.
昨天我们在挖洞的时候
And yesterday when we were digging,
我看到太阳光照射到这个家伙
I saw the glare from the sun hit this guy
在晌午时分
in the late afternoon.
看上去他就会转身
Looked like he turned away,
好似视线受阻似的
like maybe his vision was blocked.
这样还不足以越狱
It's not much of a break.
不 但这是唯一的方法
No, but it is
我们必须这么去做
one way to do what we need to do.
还有个警卫
As far as thisther guard,
必须找出他的弱点
his weakness has yet to be termined.
如果我们要和这帮警卫周旋
If we're going to get around these guys,
就必须得了解他们
we've got to get to know them.
这可没这么简单
It's not going to be easy.
只有一条正真意义上的路通往监狱
There's only one real road that goes to the prison.
我们不走大路 不用考虑了
We don't want a real road that's not an option.
怎么了?
What?
留给你兄弟的时间所剩无几
Your brother's cutting it close.
你说一周的
You said a week.
明天就周三了 可没空闲犯错了
Tomorrow's Wednesday, you didn't leave much room for error.
根本不会犯什么错
There's not going to be an"error."
听着 我有一堆事要处理 还要
Listen, I've got a lot of stuff to do and I just
那就是为何我不会浪费你的时间
Which is why I won't waste your time.
当惠斯勒出来后 我需要
When Whistler's free, I need to get to him
立刻见到他
as soon as possible.
我还在为他们逃出栅栏后
I'm still trying to work out what's going
可能发生的事情忙活着
to happen once they get past the fence.
一旦我知道所有细节 我会让你
Once I know all the details, I'll let you
林肯 冷静
Lincoln, calm down.
你让我觉得
It sounds to me like you
你们两兄弟似乎有点焦头烂额
and your brother are in over your heads.
莎拉的事 很抱歉
There's a bad joke about Sara somewhere in there.
听着
Listen
我会把详情都告诉你的
I'll let you know all the details
我一知道就会打电话给你
once I know them, and then I'll call you.
我和你们一样 希望这事能解决
I want this to work out just as badly as you do.
你比我们还急 我知道
MoreI'm sure.
LJ 呢?
LJ?
LJ 很好 你还有34个小时
LJ's fine. You have 34 hours.
她说什么了?
What did she say?
都是些废话
Nothing we don't already know.
走吧 有好多事要做呢
Let's get out of here; we got a lot of stuff to do.
瑞弗拉先生么?
Seir Rivera?
谁?
Who?
你是约格·瑞弗拉对吗?
You're Jorge Rivera, right?
索纳监狱的挖墓人?
Gravedigger at Sona?
什么事?
so?
要搭便车吗?
Would you like a ride?
不 不 有人马上来接我
No no, someone's coming to get me in a little bit.
我和你前任有个计划
I had an arrangement with your predecessor.
我想让你把这个带进监狱
I need you to get this inside the prison.
我不进监狱的
I don't go inside the prison.
他也进不去
Neither did he.
那这样吧?
How about this?
你想办法把这个
You find a way to get this delivery
送进监狱
inside the prison
只要一次就好
just this one time.
干吗要这么做?
Why would I?
因为我会给你
Becuase I would give you
5000美金
five thousand dollars.
5000美金?
Five thousand dollars?
就一次?
For just one time?
难道你不想干?
Couldn't you do that?
我想你能办到的
I think you could do it.
这样行吗?
In this?
你疯了
You're crazy
只有你可以做到
Only you can do it.
我不会让他们知道的
I wouldn't let 'em see you do that.
谁?
Who?
任何人 这是用来喝的
Anyone. It's a drinking fountain.
他们直接用嘴喝的
They put their lips right on there.
你会感觉就像美酒那样
You'd think it spits straight Jack Daniels.
知道怎么回事吗?
You understand what happened, don't you?
你就是 这里所谓的 贱民
You're a what's-it-called? a pariah.
我当初来时也犯了同样的错误
I made the same mistake when I walked in here
想要保住我的钱包
tried to hang on to my wallet.
接下来那两天 我可够惨的
Next thing I knew, I spent the next two days kneecap deep
众目睽睽之下下跪
in human feces.
在索纳 人人为己
In Sona, it's every man for himself.
来吧 蛋糕
Here, cheese.
我不饿
I'm not hungry.
会饿的
Yeah, you will be.
我看到了别的美国人
I saw the other Americans.
你们没人打过电话给大使馆 是吧?
So none of you have called the embassy, huh?
我们这些外国佬并不都是蠢蛋
Us gringos ain't all butt buddies.
要么? 不拿我就自己留着了
You want it? Cause I'll keep it.
尽快搞定吧
Let's get this done.
我们得同时盯着两个守卫
We're gonna have to watch both guards simultaneously.
你的房间得腾出来
Your cell should provide
昨天我找到了个不错的角度
a good view of the guard I saw yesterday.
盯着他做的每件事 并且记下时间
Keep track of everything he does and when he does it.
盯着他的眼睛 看他是否再次往那看
Look for that glare, see if it shows up again.
那你做什么?
What will you be doing?
观察另一个监视塔
Watching the other tower from here.
当我们做事时 得有个人放哨
While our back's turned, we're gonna need a lookout.
好吧 找马宏
Well, find Mahone.
我们不是在耍他么?
I thought we were stringing him along?
让他觉得这是真的
Looks like we're out of string.
蒂博格
Teodoro.
老大
Si, patron?
光干活 没好处 他们有话说么?
What they say about all work and no play, huh?
要放松下
Boy need his rest.
你的手下日程安排得很紧
Your clientele keeps a tight schedule.
我去看看他们有什么需要的
Got to make sure I see to their needs.
我给过你更重要的任务的
I gave you a more important task.
我没听到有什么重要事
But I haven't heard a thing.
那就多加留意点
then listen harder.
我的宝贝
Mi amor.
亲爱的
Ah, mi vida.
去我办公室
Into my office.
坐下来 看看比赛
Sit down, watch the game.
打搅 挪一下
Excuse me.
情况如何?
Anything yet?
还没情况
Nope, not yet.
你做什么的?
So what's your story, man?
我是说 接下来
I mean, the next chapter,
出去后
when we get out of here.
设想你是个工作狂
Suppose you were married to the job,
酗酒 狂躁的失眠者 或是执法人员
drank too much, rabid insomniac, typical lawman.
是啊 就像你那样惹的满身臭气
Yeah, just like you reek of live bait,
处处留情
have a girl in every port,
讲讲捕鱼的故事
tell fish stories
或者是我听到的那些
or so I've heard.
在此之前
Prior to this experience,
我可是非常尊重法律的
I had the utmost respect for the law.
这家伙都一个小时没停过了
This guy hasn't so much has scratched his jock in an hour.
要接近他可不容易啊
It's not gonna be easy to get around that guy.
我不知道
I don't know.
我们休息下吧
We might just have a break.
我去看下斯科菲尔德
I'm gonna go check on Scofield.
对不起
Sorry.
看到了吗?
Did you see the glare?
大约3点13分时 他转向右边
13 he turned to his right
有6分钟时间没注意到西面
and ignored everything to the west for six minutes,
目前就知道这些
as far as I could tell.
这家伙以为一切尽在掌握
This guy thinks he's auditioning for Buckingham Palace.
他还是个体育迷
He's also a sports fan.
他有台电视
He's got a TV.
过去四小时有两次信号不好
Twice in the last four hours the signal went fuzzy.
然后他就得调整天线
He had to turn to adjust the antennae.
我们可不能指望这啊
That's nothing we can count on.
是的
True.
但我们可以造个设备
But there is a device we can build
就用那些普通材料
out of some pretty common materials.
和收音机一样 只不过
It's almost like a radio, except it
能发送信号
transmits signals.
不好意思
Pardon me.
你新来的
You're the new guy.
是啊 你是谁?
Yeah. And who are you?
不是新来的
Not the new guy.
你要干吗?
So what's your deal?
到处逛逛 找找麻烦 怎么着?
Public intoxication, tourist in trouble what is it?
我不喜欢问太多问题的人
I don't like people asking too many questions.
我又没做错什么
when I've done nothing wrong.
那你是无辜的了
Oh, you're an innocent man.
事实上 是的
As a matter of fact, yes.
这是你第一次入狱吧?
Is this your first time in prison?
-是啊 怎么了? -因为很明显
-Uh-huh. Why? -Because it's obvious
规矩一
Rule No.1
你管好你自己的事
you mind your own business.
你知道 换是你 你也会这样的
You know, you might want to do the same.
你很清楚我在说什么
You know exactly what I'm talking about.
明白没?
You got me?
是
Yeah.
我明白
I got you.
去走走
Go take a walk.
你什么时候认识你男友惠斯勒的?
When'd you meet your boyfriend, Whistler?
在学校的最后一学期
My last year of school.
我在桑伊萨贝尔那里工作
I worked in this place in San Isabel.
他经常一个人过来
He used to come around
在吧台边坐下
by himself and sit down in a bar.
偶遇女服务员 很浪漫
Hitting on the waitress. That's romantic.
他很浪漫
He is
每次他出去
Every time he goes away,
都给我带礼物回来
he brings me back a present
这个就是
like this
这是从瑟多纳带回来的
Those are from Sedona.
他妈退休了住在那里
His mother lives there in a retirement home.
怎么了?
What's going on?
从车里出来
Out of the car, Juan Bobo
这是私人道路
This is a private road.
-我可以解释 -闭嘴
-I can explain. -Callete
要干吗?
What'd we do?
闭嘴 美国佬
Shut your uth, American.
发生什么了
u?paso
这是国家所有 车子不得通行
This is state property No vehicles allowed
索纳监狱周边两英里的路都封锁了
All roads within two miles of Sona are closed.
我们没有看到任何指示牌
We, we didn't see any signs.
你们要去哪?
Where were you going?
桑伊萨贝尔
San Isabel.
-桑伊萨贝尔? -是的
-San Isabel? -Yeah.
这是你的车吗?
This your car?
是我的
It's my car.
文件在工具箱里
The papers in the glove box.
所以我朋友不愿意来巴拿马
This is why my friends don't visit Panama.
你们警察到处惹事
You cops bother everyone.
这条路不对游客开放
This road is not for tourists.
别让我再在这里看到你
If I ever catch you out here again,
我记住你了
I'll remeber you.
不会再看到我了
It ain't gonna happen again.
好吧 快走
Okay, go on.
走吧
Anda.
你没事吧?
You okay?
没事 这办法行不通
Yeah. This is not gonna work.
-海滩离这里多远? -我不知道 大概三英里吧
-Where's the coast from here? -I don't know, maybe three miles.
好吧 实行B计划 走吧
All right, time for plan B. Come on.
再多找点过来
Found some more of these.
我们可以用吊床来做绳子
We can make rope out of this hammock.
走吧 你不是想要去那里吧
Come on. You don't want to go in there.
如果你要出去的话 我就得这么做
If you want to get out of this place I do.
待着别动
Stay here.
喂 喂 喂
he Hey Hey Hey Hey
快走
Move it
快点
Come on
这个是什么 连锁反应?
What is it, chained down?
真是千钧一发啊
It's hanging by a thread.
得等等了
It'll have to wait.
已经4:30了
It's 4:30.
-只剩下24小时不到了 -我们能搞定
-We've got less than 24 hours. -We'll make it.
-告诉我为什么? -什么?
-Tell me why.-What?
什么事情这么紧急
What's so urgent we can't get
我非得在后天之前把你弄出去?
you out of here the day after tomorrow?
我不知道 我什么都不知道
I don't know. I don't have all the answers.
你不了解我 我也不了解你
You don't me, I don't know you,
但是把我弄出去是你的任务
but it's your job to get me out of here.
晚点再过来吧
We'll come back later.
我要个这个
I'll take this as well.
-过来避暑的? -是的
Down here for the summer? Yep.
我也是这么认为 回溯到1985年
That's what I thought, back in 1985.
我有两个妻子 20年过去了
Two wives, 20 years later.
还有其他需要吗?
Want everything in here?
没了 谢谢
Yeah, thanks.
公海有多远?
International waters far out?
12海里
That's 12 nautical miles.
12海里 对吗?
12 nautical miles, huh?
就要这些了?
Is that gonna do it here?
是的
Uh, yeah.
99.25美元
$99.25.
给你
Here.
好了
All right.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你拿的是什么?
What did you get?
供给装备 你能帮我打开后车盖吗?
Supplies. Can you pop the trunk, please?
说实话我还能告诉谁?
Who am I gonna tell, honestly?
你可能是个俄罗斯间谍
You could be a Russian spy for all I know.
把这些丢了吧?
Live out of this thing?
我得做好准备
I have to be
以防不测
prepared in case of an emergency.
好吧 我们有件紧急的事
Well, we got an emergency.
除非你告诉我要去哪
I'm not going anywhere
不然我哪也不去
until you tell me where we're going.
-索拉纳海滩 -去那干吗?
Solana Beach. Why?
他们杀了莎拉
They killed Sara.
我得确保他们没杀我儿子
I'm trying to make damn sure they don't kill my son.
如果你不考虑一下
You don't think for a second
你男朋友还在监狱的话 就待在这里吧
your boy's not on that list, stay here.
我太在乎他了
I couldn't care less.
怎么了?
What is it?
是奥古斯特
It's Augusto.
他不会
He won't
再给你钱了
pay the payment for you anymore.
我每周一照例问他要钱 但是
I went to him for payment like every Monday, and
他说这不是他的职责
he said it's not his responsibility
我得问你要
and that I should ask you.
不 不 不
No, no, no, no.
你告诉奥古斯特
You tell Augusto
我不为性爱买单
I don't pay for sex.
我知道 我这么说了
I know, I did.
但是 我能做什么?
But what I do?
我找不到其他人了
I don't see anyone else
是吗?
Yeah?
我也是
Well, neither do I.
你是负责食物的?
You in charge of the food now?
不 长官 我是新来的挖墓人
No boss. I'm the new gravedigger.
你上车前
You need to sign in
要先登记
before you get on the truck.
我正准备去
I was just about to.
你读过规章手册了吗?
Have you read the rulebook?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
再好好读读
Read it again.
换句话说 我们出去之后
On the other side, when we get out of here,
会发生什么?
what's gonna happen?
我们得会一会组织的人
We're gonna meet someone from this company
当然
Apparently.
他们会杀了我
And then they're gonna kill me.
你知道的
You know that.
如果他们要杀你的话
If they wanted to kill you,
你早就死了
you'd already be dead.
我不知道他们干吗让我活着
I don't see why they keep me alive.
就像你说的 你有他们要的东西
It's like you said you've got something they want.
我告诉他们的话 我就没利用价值了
Once I give it to them, I'll be no use to them.
对吗?
Right?
我什么都不知道
I don't have all the answers.
我只知道我要把你弄出去
All I know is it's my job to get you out of here.
走吧
Let's go.
这是周三的两剂毒品 我特意给你留的
It's twofer Tuesday, my one-time special just for you.
但是不能白给你
But there's a price.
勒齐对流动资金很敏感
Lechero's getting pret sensitive about the cash flow.
我现在手头紧
Well, I'm a little short right now.
别担心 阿历克斯
No worries, Alex.
我不会让你为难的 好吗?
I am not gonna leave you hanging, all right?
我们可以给你赊账
We can just start you a tab.
他看到我们了吗?
Think he saw us?
猜猜我们能找到什么
Guess we'll find out.
我大三的时候
My third year in school,
我学的是电力工程EMP专业
we studied electrical engineering with a focus on EMPs.
EMP就是电磁脉冲的意思
That's electromagnetic pulses.
如果你把能量源放到发射器上
If you hook up a pow source to a transmitter,
就能发射电磁脉冲
it generates a pulse.
脉冲会干扰所有的电子设备
That pulse crashes anything electronic.
那是什么 就像简介
What's that, like an intro
反恐战略的简介?
an intro into anti-terrorist tactics?
差不多吧 这些天
Basically. These days,
他们教学生
they have to teach students how to defend
如何保护他们的结构
their structures.
幸运的是 那个监视塔
Fortunately for us, that guard tower is
已经造好很久了
It was engineered a long time ago.
我猜你是基础科学的常胜将军
I'm guessing you always won the elementary science fair.
把这个插上去
Plug this in.
电视信号受干扰了吗?
Did it crash the telly?
我们隔得太远了
We're too far away.
但是起作用了 正如我们需要的那样
But it is doing exactly what we need it to.
没事
Okay.
-快出来 -为什么?
Get out Why?
他们冲进来了
They're coming in.
马上离开这
Ahora mismo.
呆在这 别让人发现她
Stay here. Do not let them see her.
千万别被发现
Do not
上校
Colonel.
我们没有收到通知啊
We received no word of this
塔楼上发现了狙击枪瞄准镜
A rifle scope waseen from the tower.
胡塔多队长亲眼所见的
Capitan Hurtado saw it with his own eyes.
根本不可能
That's impossible.
狱中有把枪
There is a gun in your prison,
而且瞄准着我的人
and it was pointing at one of my men.
我们会找出来的
We are going to find it.
这看上去很不错
This looks good.
怎么说?
For what?
坐下
Have a seat.
我在这边应该
What am I supposed
干些什么呢?
to doing here?
表现的你很享受就行
Look like you're having fun.
你最后一次见到你儿子是什么时候?
When was the last time you saw your son?
林肯 你该知道的
You know, Lincoln,
我不会轻信别人
I don't automatically trust people either,
但至少我能分辨他们是否出于善意
but at least I can tell when they have good intentions.
能这样不错
Good for you.
我不会再来证明自己的立场
You know, I'm not gonna try to prove myself anymore.
我们互不相干 各忙各的
You do your job, and I'll do mine.
你需要什么?
You need something?
-你说什么? -你需要什么?
What? You need something?
不需要
No.
很好
Good.
别担心 会没事的
Don't you worry. It's all gonna be okay.
-会有麻烦的 -我向你保证
No, it's not. I promise you, I will not let
我不会让任何人发现你在这里
anyone find you in here.
勒齐一定恨死我了
Oh Lechero hate me.
勒齐不会恨你
Lechero does not hate you.
你在他心目中地位特殊
You hold a very special place in his heart.
有这么多的女孩可以取代我
So many girls can take my place.
不 他很明白 知道你比他们都好
No, he's smart. He knows you're better than them.
你是个真女子
You're a real woman.
有自己意志 自己追求的女子
A woman of her own will, her own desire.
你知道我是怎样的人
You know what I am.
妹子 这个世界上我们都是出卖自身的人
In this world, sister, we are all prostitutes.
你是女皇
You are a queen.
这是谁的狱室?
Whose cell is that?
在角上的那个?
In the corner?
是你的狱室吗?
Is that your cell?
你
You
是你的狱室吗?
Is that your cell?
是我的
It's mine
It's mine.
是我的
我找到了这个
I found this.
这不是什么武器
It's not a weapon.
我知道这是什么
I know what it is.
你为什么看我们?
Why were you watching me?
我只再问你一遍
i want to ask you one more time.
你为什么要监视我
Why were you watching me?
-我没有监视你 -我看见你了
I wasn't watching you I saw you.
回答我
Answer the question
我不知道你看到了什么 不过我真的没有监视你
I don't know what you think you saw but i wasn't watching you.
撒谎
Lie
我真的没有监视你
I wasn't watching you.
那是我的
It's mine.
你为什么监视他?
Why were you watching him?
我没有 我只是
I I wasn't. I was, uh
我在观察鸟
I was watching birds.
是的
Yes.
就是这样
看这个
See?
你之前为什么不说?
Why did you not speak up before?
我
I, uh
我很害怕
I was scared.
我真的很害怕
懦夫
Coward.
胡塔多 我们走
Hurtado Ya. Dejelo.
还差一点
Come on.
就那么一点
Come on
拜托 别这样
please, please, please.
不会吧
come on.
他要回上来了
He's coming back up here.
现在 不用担心了
Now, don't worry.
不会有什么事的
It's all going to be okay.
你脸上的妆有点掉了
You have a little mascara right there.
在他面前你得非常漂亮才行
You need to look pretty for Lechero.
谢谢
Thank you.
在这里等着吧
Wait right here.
巡逻队来过 不过他们没有久留
A patrol passed through, but they didn't stay.
乱搜了一通 然后走了
Knock some things over then walked away.
我当时让她躲在一个安全的地方
I hid your woman in a safe place,
不过说老实话
but I'd be lying
当时可真够险的
if I didn't say it was a close call.
她现在一个人待着?
Is she alone?
是的
Yeah.
你好啊
Hey.
不要害怕
Don't be afraid.
没事的 亲爱的
No, no, my dear.
他们走了
They're gone.
我想我也该走了
I should go, too.
别 别 急什么
No, no, no. What's the rush?
来吧 不要了 我要
Come on. No, I should
回家了
get home.
老大
Patr,
钱是我给她的
I gave her the money.
我先把钱给她
I was going to replace it myself
月底时候拿我的那份补上
at the end of the day, when I get my cut.
我只是一直没机会跟你汇报这事
I just didn't get a chance to tell you.
她根本没钱回家
She had no money to get home.
是这样吗?
Is this true?
是的
Yes.
我这么说没有一点不敬的意思
With all due respect.
你一定不愿让你情人一分钱不带就上路的
Surely you don't want your mistress travelin' broke.
不然的话 她就算打到车
She'd end up in a taxi
也没钱付打的费啊
with no way to pay the cab fare.
啊 你这么做
Ah, you did this?
是为了帮我的忙啊
For me?
当然了 老大
Si, patr.
蒂博格
Teodoro.
你为我可真的
The one that does all
做了好多贡献呢
the useful things for me, huh?
你是真心实意的替我着想了
And now you do the thinking for me.
也不能都这么说 老大
No, no, it's not like that, patr
去拿水桶
Get the bucket.
来给我洗脚
Wash my feet.
我们现在该怎么办
So what do we do now?
我不知道
I don't know.
这个回答可不怎么样
Well, I'm afraid that's not good enough.
得了 给我点时间考虑一下
Please just give me a moment to think.
我可不能在这里耗下去了 迈克
Wasting time is not an option for me, Michael.
我明天必须得出去
I need to be out of here by tomorrow.
我有数 赶紧出去好赶上钓鱼之旅
I know, just in time for be out your next fishing trip,omorrow.
还是 你的赏鸟之旅啊 我可记不清楚了
or is it a bird-watching trip? I forget.
那是我的航海日志 我告诉过你
That's my trip log, I've told you.
我必须按图索骥
I need to retrace my steps.
我只能按照他们吩咐的去做 你不也是嘛
I'm doing everything they tell me, the same thing you are.
你让我一个人待会行不 求你了
just, just leave me alone, please.
告诉你 我被抓起来之前
You know, before I was arrested,
一个人闯进我的公寓 拿走了我的通讯录
a man came to my flat and took my addresses.
他们知道我所在意的每个人的名字
They know the name of everyone I care about
以及如何找到他们
and how to find them.
事实上他们已经找了我所在意的每个人
Well, they already found everyone I care out. Okay?
如果你不能把我弄出去 现在就告诉我
If you can't get me out of here, tell me now.
我没有时间了
because time is running out.
明白吗?
Huh?
真是个大热天
Look, it's hot today.
是的
Yeah.
和冷天相比还是每天热点好
Prefer the heat than the cold any day.
你知道我和我兄弟准备离开这
You know my brother and I wanted to come
流亡巴拿马
down here to Panama
开家冲浪店就像我们今天去过的那家
and start a dive shop like the one we were at today.
我儿子 他应该离开学校来帮我们
My boy, he was gonna leave school and help us
打理家族生意
start the family business.
当一切了结 这有什么不可以呢?
When this is all over, why don't you do it?
发生了很多糟糕的事
Too much bad stuff's happened.
你向来都可以搞定的
Still, you can make it work.
一切都可以搞定 如果惠斯勒合作的话
It's only gonna work if if Whistler cooperates.
他玩花样 就会害了别人
he plays games, people get hurt.
你懂我的意思吗?
You understa that, right?
他并不希望任何人受伤
He doesn't want anyone to get hurt.
我希望你是对的
I hope you're right.
我想给你看点东西
I want to show you something.
我们的逃亡工具
Our getaway vehicle.
现在听好了
Now,
你下次见到他的时候
the next time you see him,
我想让你告诉他你所看到的
I want you to tell him what you saw.
告诉他我们同舟共济
Tell him we're all in this together.
我们是团队一员
We're part of a team.
你明白吗?
You understand?
好的
Okay. Yeah.
好了 走吧
All right, get up.
我们会回来的
We're coming back.
不 走这边
No, this way.
什么?
What?
是这条路 来吧
This way, come on.
好吧
Okay
如果一切顺利
If all goes well,
明天我们就可以见到他们了
we'll see them tomorrow.
干得好 谢谢
Job well done. Thank you.
我以为你说我可以得到5千美金
I thought you said I was gonna get five thousand dollars.
我就是在说这个
That's what I'm talking about.
不 不 不
Nono, no, no, no.
你说一次性付的
You said one time.
这有什么困难的?
Was it difficult?
不是这个意思
That's not the point.
一次归一次
One time is one time.
这对你我来说都好
This can work out for both of us.
如果我们今天行动
If we're gonna do this today,
我们要寻回失去的一切
we got to replace everything we lost.
比如?
Like what?
首先是一个新的出口
For starters, a new exit point.
应该开在建筑物的南边
It's got to be on the south side of the building.
又是你这个家伙
Look at this guy, again.
我认识你 对吗?
I know you, huh?
-恐怕不认识 -好吧 好吧
Afraid not. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
你是麦克法登 对吧?
You're McFadden, right?
1997年在尼斯对吗?
Nice, 1997?
抱歉
Sorry.
你认错人了
You've confused me with someone else.
肯定是你 我发誓
Yeah, yeah, yeah, I swear.
你和大使在一起
You were with the ambassador.
你把我当成别人了
You've mistaken me for someone else.
这家伙疯了
Chap's insane.
来吧 伙计们 给你们看点东西
Come on, guys, got something to show you.
我确定在你们做事的时候
I'm sure I didn't observe the guards' behavior
没有看到警察所有动作
in as much detail as you guys,
但我昨天注意到一些迹象
but I did notice something yesterday.
也是这个时间
Right around this time.
现在是换班时间
That's the day shift.
他们这批人6点就在了
They start by 6:00
继续监视
Just keep looking, keep looking.
这儿
There.
你在哪拿到的杯子 阿历克斯?
Where'd you get your cup, Alex?
在院子里 显然是他丢下的
I got it in the courtyard, but apparently it's from him.
早上有个人 午餐后还有一个
He has one in the morning and one after lunch.
会有人来接班的
Man's got to have his fix.
如果我们拿到杯子的话
If we get that cup
我们也能搞定那个家伙
We get to the man.
我们要行动了
We got to move.